Whyte, William Foote Additional Papers /4168
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William Foote Whyte Additional Papers
1923-1985
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Whyte, William Foote
/4168
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
8036158
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
A. Holland-Loucks, June 17, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
William Foote Whyte (June 27, 1914 July 16, 2000) was a sociologist chiefly known for his ethnographic study in urban sociology, Street Corner Society.[1] A pioneer in participant observation, he lived for four years in an Italian community in Boston while a Junior Fellow at Harvard researching social relations of street gangs in Boston's North End.
He joined the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University in 1948, remaining at Cornell for the remainder of his career.[1] At Cornell he supervised Chris Argyris with his doctorate. He worked for social reform and social change, directing his efforts toward "empowering the disenfranchized and narrowing the gap between rich and poor." He studied industrial and agricultural workers and workers' cooperatives in Venezuela, Peru, Guatemala and in the Basque region of Spain, as well as in the United States. He authored hundreds of articles and 20 books including an autobiography. He is considered a pioneer in industrial sociology.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4149 AV: "ASA Award Presentation to William Foote Whyte by Jacqueline Scheier" Audio-Visual Materials /4149: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4163: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4173: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4087: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4094: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4102: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4151: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4163: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4058: William Foote Whyte Office Records
Whyte, William Foote, 1914-2000
8036158
- "The Goal Book" 1931 School Yearbbok (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Swarthmore College, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Swarthmore Literary, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Swarthmore - Criticisms (College Argumentation), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- WFW Writing Bronxville Press, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- WFW Peru Letters, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- W.F Whyte's Grandfather, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mother Letters, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters from Harvard Folder [folder 1 of 2], 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters from Harvard Folder [folder 2 of 2], 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters 1940s - 1950s, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letter's 1930s [folder 1 of 3], 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bill's Letters To: Grandparents Whyte, his Parents From: Camp, college, Jugeud Laudbeciu, Sauatorium Baurustark, 1923-1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Personally Conducted 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letter's 1930s [folder 2 of 3], 1932-1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Early Writing 1930's-1940's, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Letters 1930s [folder 3 of 3], 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)